

CONTACT

Mahataraan

ghpaterson@gmail.com



www.graemepaterson.co.uk



www.linkedin.com/in/ghpaterson



www.github.com/ghpaterson

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend

- Javascript
- React
- Next
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Tailwind CSS

Backend

- Ruby
- Express
- Node
- MongoDB
- Postgres

API Development

- REST
- GraphQl

Testing

- Jest
- Cypress
- RSpec

INTERESTS



Music



Cooking



Running



Art & Design

GRAEME PATERSON

Software Developer



Creative Software Developer with over 10 years of experience as a Paramedic. Seeking to use my unique experience to make a meaningful impact on the world. I am passionate about using my skills to contribute to teams and projects that make a difference.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Developer

Alan. agency

03/2023 - present

London, UK

- Collaborated with the team to implement search features on the company website
- Streamlined layout and enhanced functionality of landing and feature pages
- Contributed to resolving a backlog of bug fixes for improved user experience

Paramedic

London Ambulance Service NHS Trust

02/2015 - 06/2023

London, UK

- Deliver the highest standard of care to Londoners while working independently.
- Emphasize teamwork with all sectors of the healthcare network to achieve the best patient outcomes.
- Continuously learn to stay ahead of the ever-evolving nature of healthcare practices.
- Possess strong attention to detail.

Paramedic

Queensland Ambulance Service

02/2013 - 12/2014

Queensland, AUS

- Deliver the highest standard of emergency care to communities in Australia.
- Utilised high levels of teamwork and creative problem solving in rural and remote communities.

EDUCATION

Makers Academy Full Stack Bootcamp

10/2022 - 02/2023

London, UK

- Collaborated daily with team members to implement TDD and OOP principles in pair programming sessions.
- Contributed to agile teams for the successful delivery of two web applications, leveraging MERN stack technologies.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Ruby and Javascript programming languages while delivering high-quality code.

Queensland University of Technology Bachelor of Applied Science (Paramedic)

02/2011 - 11/2012

Queensland, AUS

University of Queensland Bachelor of Science

02/2006 - 11/2008

Queensland, AUS

PROJECTS

Ecoliday - Personal travel carbon emissions calculator

I was part of a production team working in an agile way to bring this project to life. I was involved in every step from concept to design and implementation. This FullStack web application was built using the MERN stack to to enable people to make a more environmentally informed decision when planning a holiday. It provides users with estimated CO2e emissions for different destinations and vehicle types as well as suggesting local alternatives

Mr Bloggy - Social media app

Fullstack blog app designed for sharing and discussing your favourite things with friends. This project showcases my ability to utilise modern web technologies to develop engaging and collaborative applications. With its intuitive user interface and seamless integration with Firebase, Mr Bloggy is an excellent example of my ability to design and implement scalable web applications.